Hello this is a demonstration of the code
shared on this GitHub repository.
I have already cloned the repository to
my local folder. Let's have a look at its
contents.
This is the folder containing the time
lapse images. I am using only 40
images for this demo.
And this is the destination folder.
Outputs from 2 previous analysis are
already here.
Let's move on to the next item, the YAML
file which is used to configure the code
for specific scenarios.
You can see the destination path here.
This is where the output files will be
saved.
If you need a detailed output of the
analysis, set this to true. There are
also several other parameters that can be
tuned. For details, please
refer to the paper cited in the
repository.
This file contains the functions called
by the main script.
Now let's take a look at the main script.
This is the path to the source directory
currently hard coded to this folder.
To select the source interactively,
enable this line and disable the above
one.
Lets go ahead and run the main script.
First I need to activate the virtual
environment.
Next I'll move to the clone directory and
run the script.
The initial "just in time " ompilation
using  "NUMBA" may take some time.
Meanwhile, let's open the destination
folder.
The compilation is now complete and the
code is prompting me to select an Axon.
I'm selecting this Axon using mouse
clicks. If needed you can right Click to
remove all selected points.
Now press any key to continue.
You can see that the code is now
iterating through all the images and a
new folder has appeared in the
destination path.
The script has finished execution. Let's
check the contents of the output folder.
You can find 3 dot txt
files here. Let's open the file BEAD
chords dot txt.
This shows the coordinates of the
confirmed beads in each frame for the
selected Axon. Here we can see that
beading has started from frame number 13
onwards.
Moving on to the file bead parameters, it
contains the details of all the suspected
beads that underwent rigorous analysis.
Now let's move to the file. Rigorous
speed analysis. For each
suspected bead, it confirms whether it
was identified as a bead or not, along
with the reason if it was rejected.
Now let's quickly see how these output
data and files can be utilised.
Consider frame number 15. The file
shows that 2 beads were detected.
This should be shown in the rigorous
speed analysis file.
Now let's view these beads labeled as I
equals zero and I equals one.
Both the cropped bead and its detected
edges, along with the masks used can be
seen here.
Now let's look at the case K equals
14 and I equals zero where
a structure was rejected to be a bead.
When you look at the edges it can be seen
that there is no bead like swelling on
the edges.
Also, for each frame there is an
interactive HTML file. The
user can interact with it, see the
coordinates of the features, zoom into
the edges, etcetera.
There is also a plot of the diameter
along the Axon which allows the user to
see the peaks, their coordinates and
other related details.
Hope you found this demo useful. Thanks
for watching.